BU Records: Baylor Student Education Association, Inclusive: 1973-2002, Bulk: 1982-1989
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Baylor Student Education Association
Inclusive: 1973-2002, Bulk: 1982-1989
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/398
Baylor Student Education Association
7 oversized boxes.
The collection contains scrapbooks created by the Baylor Student Education Association (BSEA).
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
The Baylor Student Education Association (BSEA) was chartered in 1971 at Baylor University as a professional organization in the School of Education. It was the local chapter of the Texas Student Education Association (TSEA), a student affiliate of the Texas State Teachers Association and the National Education Association (NEA). The primary mission of the BSEA was threefold: preparing future teachers at Baylor through training experiences and events, encouraging highly selective standards for individuals in the teaching profession, and interesting students in teaching careers. To be a member of the BSEA, the student must have been an education major or a “friend of education” at Baylor, as well as a member of the National Education Association and Texas State Teachers Association. The organization remained active until 2009.
Scope and Content
This collection begins in 1973 and ends in 2002. The Scrapbook series includes scrapbooks created by members of the Baylor Student Education Association throughout their time on campus. Within the scrapbooks are documents from the organization, including its constitution, photographs of members, and items from various conferences the group attended.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, this collection was not arranged in a particular order. Currently, the collection is arranged in one series: Series I. Scrapbooks. Within the series, items are intellectually arranged chronologically. The majority of the collection is also physically arranged chronologically, with the exception of the items in Box 7 OVZ.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/398. Acquired 0-00-00
Related Resources
Items in related collections
BU Records: School of Education
Related references
Baylor University 2006-2007 Undergraduate Catalog. 2006 May. p. 172.
BU Records: Baylor Student Education Association, #BU/398, Box #1 OVZ, Item# 1, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Students.; Baylor University. School of Education.; Texas State Teachers Association.
Subjects
Education -- United States.
Genres
Albums (Books); Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks, 1973-2002; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series includes several scrapbooks created by members of the organization over time. Some scrapbooks were removed from their covers and placed in folders for preservation purposes. This series is in average condition.
  - Scrapbook: “B. S. E. A.”, 1973 (Box 1 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook: “BSEA”, 1981-1982 (Box 1 OVZ, Item 2)
  - Scrapbook: “Up Up & Away with BSEA (1 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 2 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook: “Up Up & Away with BSEA (2 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 2 OVZ, Item 2)
  - Scrapbook: “The Wonderful World of BSEA” (1 of 2), 1984-1985 (Box 2 OVZ, Item 3)
  - Scrapbook: “The Wonderful World of BSEA” (2 of 2), 1984-1985 (Box 2 OVZ, Item 4)
  - Scrapbook: “School Days Dear Old Golden BSEA days”, 1985-1986 (Box 3 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook: “BSEA Connection”, 1986-1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook: “Baylor TSEA, Master the Possibilities, Dr. James Wiley, sponsor,”, 1987-1988 (Box 7 OVZ, Item 2)
  - Scrapbook: “Baylor Student Education Association”, 1988-1989 (Box 3 OVZ, Item 2)
  - Scrapbook: “Education is a HOT Topic”, 1989-1990 (Box 4 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook: “Baylor”, circa 1990-1992 (Box 4 OVZ, Item 2)
  - Scrapbook: “BSEA”, 1992-1993 (Box 4 OVZ, Item 3)
  - Scrapbook: “Baylor Student Education Assoc.”, 1993-1994 (Box 4 OVZ, Item 4)
  - Scrapbook: “Baylor Student Education Association 1994-1995 presentsEL BEAR TALES” (Box 5 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook: “BSEA”, 1995-1996 (Box 5 OVZ, Item 2)
  - Scrapbook: “Step into the future of education”, circa 1996-1997 (Box 5 OVZ, Item 3)
  - Scrapbook: “Teachers put the pieces together, Baylor Student Education Association”, 1998-1999 (Box 6 OVZ, Item 1)
  - Scrapbook: “Open the Doors to the Future”, 2001-2002 (Box 6 OVZ, Item 2)